Guide to the James Kirkup Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Visual Material, late 1800s-2000s; Series V; 2.29; (6 boxes)
  - Photographs
    - Family photographs, late 1800s (Box 179, Folder 1736-1737)
    - Family and childhood photographs, late 1800s-1920s (Box 180, Folder 1738-1741)
    - England and James Kirkup, including negatives, 1930s-1950s (Box 180, Folder 1742-1746)
    - Family photographs and postcards, 1930s-1990s (Box 181, Folder 1747)
    - James Kirkup in Japan, including negatives, late 1950s (Box 181, Folder 1748-1749)
    - Family photographs, including negatives, 1940s-1950s (Box 181, Folder 1750-1752)
    - Sweden, including negatives, 1950s (Box 181, Folder 1753-1754)
    - England, 1950s (Box 181, Folder 1755)
    - J. R. Ackerley, 1950s (Box 181, Folder 1756)
    - Japan, 1960s (Box 181, Folder 1757)
    - Portraits of James Kirkup, 1940s-1960s (Box 181, Folder 1758)
    - Snapshots and portraits of James Kirkup, including negatives, 1960s (Box 182, Folder 1759-1762)
    - Newcastle, 1973 (Box 182, Folder 1763-1765)
    - Snapshots and portraits of James Kirkup, including negatives, 1960s-1970s (Box 182, Folder 1766-1771)
    - Snapshots and portraits of James Kirkup, including negatives, 1970s-1990s (Box 183, Folder 1772-1782)
    - Kowalczyk photographs, 1983 (Box 183, Folder 1783)
    - Reproductions of photographs of South Shields, 1983-1988 (Box 183, Folder 1784)
    - Photographs of an exhibition at South Tyneside Libraries, printouts, 2006 (Box 184, Folder 1785)
    - Black and white duplicate prints of photographs from various times, undated (Box 184, Folder 1786-1797)
    - Papers found with photographs, undated (Box 184, Folder 1798)
    - Black and white duplicate prints of school photographs, undated
  - Other Visual Material
    - Drawing of James Kirkup by James Curry, pencil, 1940s (Box 184, Folder 1799)
    - Collages by James Kirkup, undated (Box 184, Folder 1800)
    - Painting by James Kirkup: Clowance Wood, Horse Downs, undated (Box 184, Folder 1801)
    - Painting by James Kirkup: Landscape, 1943
    - Pencil sketches: of a woman lying down with a flute, and of a figure swimming, undated (Box 184, Folder 1802)
- Printed Material, 1930s-2000s; Series VI; 3.13; (8 boxes) + 1 roll and 4 broadside folders
  Clippings and ephemera are arranged roughly chronologically. Posters and broadsides are listed at the end of the series.
  Printed material (Series VI) consists of clippings, ephemera, and posters. Clippings include works by and about James Kirkup. Ephemera includes theater programs. Posters feature poems by Kirkup and others, or promote plays Kirkup wrote or translated.
  - Clippings (Reviews of Kirkup's works), 1950s-1960s (Box 185, Folder 1803-1847)
  - Clippings (Reviews of Kirkup's works) (continued), 1950s-1960s (Box 186, Folder 1848-1882)
  - Clippings (Reviews of Kirkup's works) (continued), 1950s-1960s (Box 187, Folder 1883-1896)
  - "Lecture programs", 1950s-1960s (Box 188, Folder 1897)
  - Clippings related to Noh, 1960s-1970s (Box 188, Folder 1898)
  - Ephemera: Poetry Fair at Toganji Temple in Nagoya, 1970 October 10-11
  - Ephemera: English Music Theatre Company, 1970s (Box 188, Folder 1899)
  - Clippings and ephemera related to AIDS, 1980s-1990s (Box 188, Folder 1900-1901)
  - Clippings: "Idiots Savants", 1990s (Box 188, Folder 1902)
  - Clippings: "Latin America", 1990s (Box 188, Folder 1903)
  - Clippings: "British", 1990s (Box 189, Folder 1904)
  - Clippings: "German", 1990s (Box 189, Folder 1905)
  - Clippings related to Claude Lucas, 1997 (Box 189, Folder 1906)
  - Clippings related to World War I, 1999 (Box 189, Folder 1907)
  - Clippings: "French Cinema", 1990s-2000s (Box 189, Folder 1908)
  - Clippings: "Theater", 1990s-2000s (Box 189, Folder 1909)
  - Clippings: "Spanish", 2000s (Box 189, Folder 1910)
  - Ephemera: small cards in Japanese ("Tohoku"), undated (Box 189, Folder 1911)
  - Unsorted clippings and ephemera, 1930s-2000s (Box 190, Folder 1912-1920)
  - Unsorted clippings and ephemera (continued), 1930s-2000s (Box 191, Folder 1921-1927)
  - Unsorted clippings and ephemera (continued), 1930s-2000s (Box 192, Folder 1928-1943)
  - Posters and broadsides, 1969-2000
  - Posters and broadsides, undated (Box ROLL, Folder 1944)
  - Broadsides: Poem of the Month, undated
  - Posters: Bewick Bestiary, undated (Box BSD, folder 1945)
  - Posters: Bewick Bestiary, undated (Box BSD, folder 1946)
  - Theater Posters, 1955, undated (Box BSD, folder 1947)
  - Posters, undated (Box BSD, folder 1948)
- Manuscript Material Removed From Books, 1960s-2000s; Series VII; 0.42; (1 box)
  Manuscript Material Removed From Books (Series VII) consists of correspondence, notes and ephemera removed from books that were transferred to Printed Acquisitions to be cataloged. The correspondence in this series relates chiefly to the accompanying books.
  - Manuscript material removed from books, 1960s-2000s (Box 193, Folder 1949-1959)
- Oversize Material, 0.83; (5 boxes) + 1 roll
  - Lawson, Sonia (Series I), 1940s? (Box 194, Folder 1960)
  - Unsorted general correspondence (Series I), undated (Box 194, Folder 1961)
  - Poems, drafts, holograph and typescript (Series II), undated (Box 195, Folder 1962)
  - An Actor's Revenge, Score, manuscript and printed version (copies) (Series II), undated (Box 195, Folder 1963-1965)
  - Candle in the Heavens, drafts, holograph and typescript, and related correspondence (Series II), 1955 (Box 196, Folder 1966)
  - Cloak of Feathers, typescript (copy) (Series II), undated (Box 196, Folder 1967)
  - The Disappearing Boy, typescript (copy) (Series II), undated (Box 196, Folder 1968)
  - Friends in Arms ("Achilles") (opera libretto), manuscript (copy) (Series II), undated (Box 196, Folder 1969)
  - The Magic Drum, typescript (Series II), undated (Box 196, Folder 1970)
  - The Peach Garden, holograph and typescript (Series II), undated (Box 196, Folder 1971)
  - The Pot of Poison, typescript (copy) (Series II), undated (Box 196, Folder 1972)
  - The Silken Drum (libretto), draft and notes, typescript and holograph (Series II), 1984, undated (Box 196, Folder 1973-1974)
  - Two Pigeons Flying High, typescript (Series II), 1955 (Box 196, Folder 1975)
  - [Various titles], music with words by James Kirkup, printed versions and related correspondence (Series II), 1950s-1970s (Box 196, Folder 1976)
  - Obituaries by James Kirkup, notes and clippings (Series II), 1990s (Box 197, Folder 1977-1978)
  - Yamaguchi, Seishi. The Essence of Modern Haiku, proof and related correspondence (Series II), 1992 (Box 197, Folder 1979)
  - Yamaguchi, Takeyoshi. "A Preliminary Checklist of the Writings of James Kirkup," notes, typescripts, and printed version (Series II), 1978 (Box 197, Folder 1980)
  - Japan Festival Fund Award (Series III), 1997 (Box 197, Folder 1981)
  - Certificates, World Academy of Arts and Culture (Series III), 1984 (Box 197, Folder 1982)
  - Family and childhood photographs (Series V), early 1900s (Box 197, Folder 1983)
  - Portraits of James Kirkup (Series V), 1940s? (Box 197, Folder 1984)
  - Painting by James Kirkup: Landscape (Series V), 1943 (Box 197, Folder 1985)
  - Ephemera: Poetry Fair at Toganji Temple in Nagoya (Series VI), 1970 October 10-11 (Box 198, Folder 1986)
  - Unsorted clippings and ephemera (Series VI), 1930s-2000s (Box 198, Folder 1987)
  - Posters and broadsides (Series VI), 1969-2000 (Box 198, Folder 1988)
  - Broadsides: Poem of the Month (Series VI), undated (Box 198, Folder 1989)
  - Black and white duplicate prints of school photographs (Series V), undated (Box ROLL, Folder 1990)
- Restricted Fragile Material, 0.42; (2 boxes)
  - Reel-to-reel audio tapes (Series IV) (Box 199, Folder 1991-1993)
  - Reel-to-reel audio tapes (Series IV) (Box 200, Folder 1994-1995)